Patrick Motsebo

: motsebo@gmail.com

: 309-532-7479

http://www.patcindy-biz.com/PatResume_web.html

: https://patkloe.github.io/portfolio/

: Memphis, TN 38115

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Summary:

I am a full stack developer with a 360-degree view on product development process. I am focused on web quality, keep learning more software languages, client and server sides to develop products for customer satisfaction.

- Always, high motivated, self-learner, people person.
- Having worked with some corporate for their website developments. Developed websites such as

Websites	Technology	Dates
http://www.patcindy-biz.com	Mvc, aspx, Html5, Css3, JQuery	May 2016
http://www.georgiagames.org/	Css3, Html5, Dhtml, Xhtml, Xml, Flash, ActionScript, JQuery, Json, JavaScript,, S.E.O	Mar 2010 - Aug 2010
http://www.ubia.fr/	Css2, ASP, Flash, ActionScript, PHP4, Dhtml, Html4, Sql, S.E.O, JavaScript	Jun 2008 – Sep 2008
http://touchofgodministries.org/en/overview/	Joomla, Jreview,Html, Php, JavaScript	Jan 2008 – Mar 2008
http://www.gospel-river.com/fr/Accueil- Gospel-River.htm	Asp, html4, Css2,C# Photoshop, JavaScript	Sep 2006 – Oct 2007
https://www.jeremiesion.com/fr/	Css, PHP4, Dhtml, Html, Sql,Javascript, Json, S.E.O, Joomla 1.5, Drupal 5	Jun 2003 – Dec 2007

- Over 5 years of experience in Developing video, Scripts with Flash ActionScript and Java Script for the ecommerce website
- Have expertise over Search Engine Optimization.
- Developed in school : some applications with Java, PL/SQL
- Change theme with Drupal(Drupal theming), Add modules, manage users

Skills:

Operating Systems: Windows 2003/2008 Server, Windows 2000, XP, Vista, 7, 10, Linux Redhat, Mandrake.

Web server: Apache, IIS

Internet/Network Protocol: Http, TCP/IP, Ftp, Dhcp, Dns. Comet, isp

Systems: Linux (mandrake, Redhat, Fedora), Windows (Xp, Vista, Nt, 7, advance server, 2003),

Macos

CMS: Joomla, Dotnetnuke.

Languages: Python, Php, Java, C, {C#, REACT.js, VUE.js, Angular.js} - "learning"

Web: Html5/CSS3/ JavaScript.

Relational databases: Dbase, MySQL, Oracle, Access, SQLite

PHP/ (JavaScript and Html) Framework: Windows framework 4.0, Laravel, Bootstrap4, Font

Awesome

Best Practices: SEO (Search Engine Optimization) **Development Methodology, Tools** agile, Git, GitHub

Other: Camtasia, filemaker, office 2007, xp, Git, Putty, Winscp, skills on section 508

Professional Experiences:

Currently (working Freelance)

Jan 2020

For some customers, working remotely on their websites using Joomla. Html, Css, JavaScript, MySQL, Php.

Deploy Updates files to their servers through FileZilla. GitHub, Heroku

Jabil Inc. Circuit, Memphis, TN

Mar 2011 - Dec 2019

Web developer

Responsibilities:

• Developed web pages using "PHP/MySQL/jpgraph "module for pie chart"
Retrieved data from the database server MySQL through PHP scripts, used Jpgraph to build pie charts, based on data provided to the jpgraph classes ("lines, 3D" plot) called.

Statefarm insurance, Bloomington, IL Web analyst

Sept 2010 - Feb 2011

web analyst

Responsibilities:

• Retrieved datas from the database server Mysql through php scripts, provided those datas to Xcelsius which will

generate a .swf file, insert that file on html page through javascript (embed the object swfobject) **Georgia games,** Kennesaw, GA

Sept 2009 - Aug 2010

Georgia games, Kennesaw, GA Web Application Developer

Responsibilities:

• Updated the current Website http://georgiagames.org/index.html

Sometimes, worked at home, using ftp application to download and upload the file on the server, using Html, Dhtml, JavaScript, Xml, and Xhtml.

Cm2s, Paris, France

June 2009 – Aug 2009

Senior/Web Application Developer

Responsibilities:

- Coordinated change control procedures with existing support and managed groups, Served as a Link with programmers & engineers resolving technical problems with business applications and hardware configurations
 - Developed websites with content management system: joomla, jreview and Drupal.
 MySQL
 - Developed some websites using Html, Dhtml, JavaScript, ActionScript, Xml, Xhtml,Css, S.E.O

Thelligence International PARIS, FRANCE **Web Application Developer**

Responsibilities:

- Developed Web application using **MVC** technology to assist customers.
- Created Videos with **Flash**, created Banners, Images with Photoshop, Illustrator.
- Worked with File Transfer Protocol (FTP) to load files on server
- Managed web domain of customer mail accounts and database administration accounts
- Created graphics design on websites to advertise clients information
- Worked on threaded discussion group access and displayed in a variety of formats using PHP/MySQL, Css, JQuery and JavaScript (both client-side and server-side), S.E.O
- Developed video, 3D Scripts with Flash, ActionScript for the Customers Websites
- Developed and maintained some websites, using Html, Dhtml, JavaScript, Dreamweaver, Flash, Photoshop, Illustrator

Education:

Currently taking programming class at Tech901 – Memphis. TN

- Master Degree in Computer Science at Orsay's Faculty of Sciences-France
- Bachelor of Science, Computer science at Luminy faculty of sciences-France
- "HTML5/CSS3" intermediate certificate from Kennesaw state University.
- Currently code 1.0 at Tech901 Memphis, TN
- CS50 Certificate from Harvard University Computer-sciences and (Programming)